hello and welcome to the 33rd tutorial
on how to program eg script 2.
so in this tutorial i want to show a
couple of different things
first let's open our weapons
and create a new weapon
let's call it just call it
stuff
okay because we're gonna have a lot of
stuff in it
then let's add it to ourselves um
function
client side
then we're gonna put
uh find
weapon no find player
then my my name or my account girl
then
dot
add weapon
and the name of this weapon this dot
name
and i should have that weapon so i apply
that
press q and
it's not there
apply that
stuff there it is
maybe it was there before i didn't
notice it oh well
so next what we want to do is
put we can delete all this
let's put client side so client side
and let's create
an array
so previously in previous tutorials i've
been using
said array
then whatever array name i want or
like asfd then how many i want
well as you know as you know this is the
g-script one version of said array
and what i recently found out is the
g-skip 2 version
which took a while to figure out um
we have to do
is put parentheses
and then in it put
whatever variable you want to be in the
array like this dot
hello
then comma how many you want so let's
put 10.
so now we have 10 variables of this dot
hello
and you can do any prefix you want you
can put this dot
you can put temp dot
whatever you want let's put this dot
so this adds a lot more functionality to
your arrays you can add
different types of variables now
so let's just test it out let's put
this dot hello uh
five
is equal to
hey
and then let's put this dot hello
uh four is equal to
no
let's just also let's make this less
let's put just five
then we'll put zero one
and we'll just copy this
so now we have six we want five so there
then let's increase these differently
into different numbers three four
remember it has to go up to four only it
can't go to five because zero counts as
one of the numbers
okay so now we have that we can do a for
loop or something for
uh what verb we want
and template n is equal to
zero
and as long as temp dot n
is less than five the amount of
variables in this array
then it's going to keep looping then
temp dot n
plus plus
and over here let's put
uh player.chat
is equal to
this dot hello
and n
to show which
variable in the array we want to specify
which is all five because we're putting
n and it's looping through through the
end
and
that's it let's put a sleep here
one second and run that
let's just say no hey no
hey
and then it just stops because the for
loop
is over n is five now and it's broken
so that's how you use arrays in g script
two
now another thing i want to show you
let's create an image show image
and we're going to put
block.png
you can do whatever image you want
then let's put
uh player.x comma player.y so as soon as
i update the weapon the image is going
to appear
on the coordinates of my player
so let's hit that
see if it works yep it works there's an
image here now
now
there's something about images you
probably don't know
you can do a lot of different
changes you can change them in a lot of
different ways
so let's type
with find image
and then put the image we want to find
parenthesis to end it and brackets now
what this is going to do
is find
this image
and whatever we're going to put in here
is going to be applied to this image
now you must have this after the image
has already been called you can't have
it before
so let's put
let's put something like
zoom equals two
you can do this with any any image
remember that if we hit apply the image
is twice as big now
we can also put
uh 0.5
or 0.3 or 0.2
and it'll be really small you can barely
see it right there
let's just make it two to make it bigger
other than that you can also change the
colors
let's do that let's go here
and let's put
red
green
blue
okay now these are the three colors you
can change
by default
these are all equal to one by default
so if you don't specify them they're
just going to be one
now if you just have them at one all the
colors of the image are going to be
there
however if we change one of them to
let's say we'll change the rate to 0.5
all of the red in that image is going to
be
taken away by half so now you get this
tealish aquaish greenish color here
now if we took out red completely
zero
um took out all green
it would be blue
if we took out
a minimal zero
it'd be a totally black image
because there's no color in it
which is pretty useful you can
change colors around but for us let's
just put something at random like 0.8
uh
0.2 and 0.5
it's kind of ugly but whatever
then over here
let's put another command let's put
alpha
now this is how much
alpha you want the image to have like
invisibility if you put it at one
it's going to be totally visible
if we put it at
0.6
it's going to be
sort of invisible
if you put it at zero
it's going to be totally invisible
now here's the thing with alpha
point let's put it at 0.9 it doesn't
look very good kind of
if we want it to look like a better
transparency
right before the alpha add mode equals
one
as you can see
it it's it's better looking transparency
let's put this alpha point five and i'll
show you the difference again this is
with mode equals one
and let's take that out
and this is
without mode equals one
see the difference
so i usually put mode equals one because
it looks better i'm not sure why this
does it but if you want it to look
better then just put more equals one
all right so some more things you can do
is
go in here and put
stretch
x and we're going to put another one
y
now what you're going to do is stretch
the image
on these two axises
by whatever number you put if you just
put one and then put a one here
it's not gonna do anything as you can
see by default is one
now if we go here and put x as point
i don't know point point five and put y
is
ten
watch what happens
whoa
that's pretty
stretched
uh let's make it a bit less just two
let's continue you can stretch the
images too now you can combine all these
things zoom
stretch
colors alpha you can combine them all
another thing you can do is
let's just delete all this with find
image here
and go here and instead of player x
player y just put
10 comma 10. so if we update this it
should appear
coordinates 10 comma 10.
now if you look here 10 comma 10 puts it
into the level so it's at the
coordinates 10 comma 10 on the level
now let's say that we don't want it to
be on the level we want it to be on the
screen for example we could have our own
little heart system here that shows
heart images and it moves as we move
and uh goes to every other level
well as long as weapon
well what we could do is go here and put
change
img for image then vis
then parentheses
so
in the parenthesis put the id of the
image hours is 300
and then put a number
and the number we're looking for is 9.
so put that there
now if you look here well you can't
actually see it i'm going to put
100 instead
as you can see
it appears at the coordinates 100 comma
100 kind of hard to you to tell because
you can't really see the very top left
of my game screen but this will put it
at the coordinates 100 comma 100 by
pixel so now if we move around
it you can see the levels moving
it's kind of hard to tell but
look at this npc here for an example you
can see i'm moving but the npc i mean
the image isn't moving because it's on
my screen at the coordinates 10 100 100
this is by pixel now you can do the same
thing with anything that has an id with
it
now if we put another number like i
don't know zero
hit that well i don't know what that
does but if we put one
uh
wait
i don't want
a hundred hundred i want ten ten
well the image
again appears at coordinates 10 comma 10
on the level
now all of these numbers do something
else do something different i believe
i only know one
and nine
one for level
and nine for pixels you can try out some
other things but i don't know if someone
won't even do anything
well anyway that's change image biz
so now you know more about editing the
uh
images and other things that have
these
id's
so i guess this is that's the end of
this tutorial
now this will probably be the last tour
i'm going to make because my server time
is almost out
uh
i hope you learned
how to use descript 2
and can now make
some actual pretty good things now with
it
you can make your own health systems you
can make
weapons that you
press space or something and then it
hits the other players
you know things like that
and
i hope you make some good things of that
that concludes this tutorial and
bye